Do I smell... miso soup?
味噌汁の…匂い？
本字幕由诸神字幕组出品，仅供学习交流，禁止用于商业用途
更多中日双语字幕，尽在 www.kamigami.org 和微博 @诸神字幕组
诸神微信公众号正式上线啦，搜索「诸神字幕组」添加关注吧
Good morning.
お早う御座います
What?
そ
の
重
い
足
を
膝
前
へ
導
く
sono omoi ashi o hiza o mae ni michibiku
That feeling pulls your feet onward,
その重い足を膝を前へ導く
负
责
人
Maki
负责人
chikara nanda tte Go ahead to
Telling you to go ahead towards a new power.
力
は
何
だ
っ
て
Go
ahead
問
う
力は何だって Go ahead 問う
君
の
中
に
生
じ
る
衝
動
は
treasure
kimi no naka ni shoujiru shoudou wa Treasure
That impulse born within you is a treasure!
君の中に生じる衝動はtreasure
honmon ka nisemono ka tsureteike yo
Whether it's real or fake, just take it along!
日
听
小
伍
长
田
Cris
翻
译
兰
樱
Naga
校
对
小
伍
江
本
物
か
偽
物
か
つ
れ
て
行
け
よ
日听
小伍
长田Cris
翻译
兰樱
Naga
校对
小伍
小江
本物か偽物か つれて行けよ
kuusou no kanata notte boku no mata mo taemai yo
Straddling the limits of this fantasy, my legs probably won't last,
空
想
の
彼
方
ま
で
僕
の
中
怠
慢
よ
空想の彼方まで 僕の中の怠慢よ
soredemo ii yo yume demo
But that's just fine, even if it's only a dream.
时
间
轴
阿
水
压
制
Coolkid
さ
ら
っ
て
も
い
よ
夢
で
も
时间轴
阿水
压制
Coolkid
さらってもいいよ 夢でも
todokisou de todokanai Make some noise
It seems within reach, but somehow too far off, so make some noise!
届
き
そ
う
で
届
か
な
い
make
some
noise
届きそうで届かない make some noise
Are these empty days gonna start shining bright?
kuukyo na nichijou wa kagayakidasu noka
空
虚
な
日
常
は
輝
き
出
す
の
か
空虚な日常は輝き出すのか
吐
き
出
す
よ
う
に
し
て
前
に
漕
げ
ば
hakidasu you ni shite mae ni mae ni kogeba
If we push on through like we're about to hurl,
吐き出すようにして前に前に漕げば
bokura no mirai wa kasoku shiteyuku darou
I'm sure our future will start to pick up speed!
僕
ら
の
未
来
は
加
速
し
て
い
く
だ
ろ
う
僕らの未来は加速していくだろう
今
こ
の
時
が
止
ま
る
と
し
て
も
ima kono toki ga tomaru to shitemo kono kokyuu made
Even if this moment in time becomes frozen,
今この時が止まるとしても
こ
の
呼
吸
ま
で
止
め
ら
れ
は
し
な
い
さ
この呼吸まで止められはしないさ
tomerare wa shinai sa kudaranai gohoubi mada?
There's no stopping this breath, so where's my worthless reward?
く
だ
ら
な
い
くだらない
ご
褒
美
ま
だ
？
ご褒美まだ？
I wasn't told we were
going to be roommates!
同棲なんて聞いてませんよ
部屋が足りなくてね
We don't have enough rooms, you see.
But...
しかし…
She agreed.
彼女は同意してるよ
指示なら
It was an order.
Don't you get it, Atsushi-kun?
わからないかい　敦君
Get what?
何です
Without any kin,
she's as alone as can be.
縁者もいない彼女は　沼の中のように孤独だ
Besides, the Port Mafia
might send assassins after her.
それに　組織の刺客が来るやもしれない
That's true.
確かに
You should protect her.
君が守るんだ
Okay, I'll do my best!
わかりました　頑張ります
If you have the time to mess with Atsushi,
敦で遊んどる暇があったら　ポートマフィアに囚われた件の報告書を出せ
write up the report about your
capture by the Port Mafia!
Atsushi-kun.
敦君
Yes?
はい
Write the report for me.
私の代わりに報告書を書きたまえ
What?
It'll be about the person who
placed a bounty on your head.
君に懸賞金を懸けた黒幕の話でもかい
You found out who it was?
わかったんですか
According to the Port Mafia's
communication records,
ポートマフィアの通信記録に拠ると
出資者は「ギルド」と呼ばれる北米異能者集団の団長だ
the bounty was placed by
the leader of The Guild,
a North American organization of the gifted.
The Guild is considered an urban legend.
「ギルド」は都市伝説の類だぞ
Their agents are said to hold key positions
in finance, politics, and the military.
構成員は政財界や軍閥の要職を担う一方で
They're a secret society who
use their limitless funds
裏では膨大な資金力と異能力で幾多の謀を底巧む秘密結社
and abilities to plot countless schemes.
Why would such a group want Atsushi?
そんな連中が何故敦を…
We have a probem!
大変です
It seems we've been provoked.
先手を取られたね
Episode 12
Borne Back
Ceaselessly
Into the Past
Pleasure to finally meet you,
会えてとても嬉しいよ　プレジデント・フクナ…
President Fukuna.
Fukuda?
フクダ？
Fukuzawa.
福沢
That's right!
それだ
By the way, was it a bad move to
park the heli on the road?
ところで　ヘリを道路に停めさせたが　まずかったかね？
You've come a long way
from a foreign land.
外国の方が遠路遥々ご苦労でしたな
して要件は
So, what do you wish to discuss?
ほう　珍しいデザインだ
Well, this is a rare design.
陶磁器には詳しい心算だったが　どこの銘柄かな
And I do consider myself
something of an expert in porcelain.
What brand is this?
Royal Blanc?
ロイヤル・ブラン？
Or is it perhaps El Zelga?
或いはエル・ゼルガか
It's from Shimomura China and
Ceramics, next door.
隣の下村陶器店です
Oh, my apologies.
それは失礼
Call me Francis, old sport.
俺のことはフランシスと呼んでくれ　親友
北米本国で「ギルド」という寄合を束ねている
I lead an organization called
The Guild in North America.
In addition, I personally own
その他　個人的に三つの複合企業と五つの宿泊亭
three conglomerates, five hotels,
それに航空会社と鉄道…
an airline, a railway company, and—
フランシス殿
Mr. Francis.
I have received reports that
you placed a bounty
貴君は懸賞金でポートマフィアを唆し　我々を襲撃させたとの報告があるが
that encouraged the Port Mafia to attack us.
Is this true?
誠か
Yes, that was my mistake.
ああ　あれは過ちだったよ
I had no idea that this country's
criminal organizations
まさかこの国の非合法組織があれほど役立たずとは
would be so incompetent.
To make amends, I come bearing
a profitable business deal.
謝罪にいい商談を持ってきた
This company isn't so bad.
この会社は悪くない　街並みも美しいしな
The neighborhood is quite nice, as well.
So,
そこでだ
I'd like to buy this company.
この会社を買いたい
Don't get me wrong,
勘違いするな
I am quite capable of
buying all the properties
俺はここから見える土地と会社凡てを買うこともできる
visible from here along with your company.
I have no interest in this
building or your employees.
この社屋にも社員にも興味はない
I am only interested in one thing.
あるのは一つ
You don't mean...
まさか
Yes, I do.
そうだ
異能開業許可証を寄越せ
Hand over your Gifted Business Permit.
For a group of gifted individuals
to legally open a business,
この国で異能力者の集まりが合法的に開業するには
they need a permit issued by the Ministry of
Internal Affairs' Gifted Operations division.
内務省異能特務課が発行した許可証が必要だ
Those blockheads are about the only
ones you can't buy with money.
特務課の石頭どもだけは金で買収できない
After all, we are a secret society
with no official existence.
何しろ表向きはないことになっている秘密組織だ
In order to keep peace with the Ministry
連中を敵に回さず　大手を振ってこの街で「探し物」をするには
and be able to find
what we're looking for in this city,
the permit is—
その許可証が…
断る
I refuse.
What, this isn't enough?
なんだ　これでは足りんか
Then I'll add this.
それでは　これもつけよう
It's a limited edition model,
限定生産で特注ダイヤがあしらわれた逸品だ
made to order with diamonds.
Just as lives cannot be bought with money,
命が金で買えぬように　許可証と替えられるものなど存在せぬ
nothing is worth giving up our permit.
The permit is the beating
heart of this Agency.
あれは社の魂だ
特務課の期待
It embodies the hope of
the special ops division,
許可証発行に尽力していただいた夏目先生の想いが込められている
as well as the spirit of Natsume-sensei,
who worked tirelessly to
get the permit for us.
頭に札束の詰まった成金が易々と触れてよい代物ではない
It is not meant to easily fall into
the hands of the filthy rich,
who have dollar bills for brains.
So you're saying there are things
you can't buy with money?
「金で買えないものがある」か
That's the mantra of the poor.
貧乏人の決め台詞だな
Your bravado is pointless if all
of your employees disappear
いくら君が強がっても　社員が皆消えてしまっては　会社は成り立たない
and your agency ceases to function.
そうなってから意見を変えても遅いぞ
It'll be too late to change your mind then.
I'll take your advice to heart.
ご忠告　心に留めよう
I suggest you leave.
帰したまえ
I'll be back.
また来る
Our visitors are leaving.
お客様のお帰りでーす
Okay!
はーい
I'll see you out!
お送りします
I'll post a message
in the morning newspaper.
明日の朝刊にメッセージを載せる
Take a good look at it, old sport.
よく見ておけ　親友
I always get what I want.
俺は欲しいものは必ず手に入れる
Nice hat.
その帽子素敵ね
Oh, really?
そうですか　有り難う御座います
Thank you.
Well?
どう　似合うかしら
Does it look good on me?
You'd look better in burlap sack.
麻袋でも被ったほうがマシだな
What was that for?
何よ
Hmph.
First, there was one.
先ずは一人
The
Follo-
wing
Mor-
ning
The
Follo-
wing
Mor-
ning
Hey, did you see the morning news?!
おい　朝刊を見たか
It's on TV, too.
報道でもやってるよ
Please see for yourself.
ご覧ください
A seven-story building
has vanished overnight.
七階建ての建物が一夜にして消滅してしまいました
According to one source,
一部情報筋では消滅した建物にはポートマフィアのフロント企業が入っており
the building housed a front
company for the Port Mafia.
It was allegedly used as
an office by their agents.
構成員の事務所として使われていたとの情報もあります
So this is the message.
メッセージとはこれか
彼らを送って出た賢治君も矢張り寮にはいませんでした
Kenji-kun hasn't been back to
the dorm since seeing them off.
So they'll annihilate
anyone who opposes them,
逆らう探偵社も　用済みのマフィアも　凡て消すか
be it the Port Mafia or the Agency.
Tanizaki, from now on, you're
prohibited from working alone!
谷崎　これ以上単独で動くな
Look for Kenji with Atsushi!
敦と組んで賢治を探せ
Dazai, you're with me!
太宰は俺と一緒に来い　社長会議だ
We need to meet with the president.
We don't know what kind of
gifts they possess.
どんな能力を持ってるかわからん
If you make contact with the enemy,
敵と接触しても　戦わずに逃げろ
don't engage them, run!
Okay.
はい
Naomi, you should go back to the Agency.
ナオミ　矢っ張り社に戻るんだ
It's too dangerous.
危険すぎる
They can make entire buildings disappear.
建物ごと消せるんだから　どこに行っても同じよ
Elise-chan?
エリスちゃん　頼むから出てきておくれ
It doesn't matter where I am.
Please come out, okay?
Right, Atsushi-san?
ねぇ　敦さん
W-Well, sure.
ま…まあ
おーい
Atsushi-kun!
敦君
Elise-chan, please.
Unlike you, my sister isn't gifted!
エリスちゃん　お願い
君と違って　妹には異能力がない
足を引っ張る
She'll hold us back.
Elise-chan?
エリスちゃん
How dare you!
何よ　兄様
Where are you?
You said you'd do anything I said!
ナオミの云うことは何でも聞くって云ったじゃない
どこだい
おーい
That was yesterday when you were forcing me to—
昨日のアレはお前が無理矢理…
エリスちゃん
Nothing.
何でもありません
Anyways, it's too dangerous, so go back!
とにかく危険だから戻るんだ
Oh, really?
あらあら　なんなら昨日の懇願を思…
If you'd like, I can help
you remember how it felt—
Naomi?
ナオミ？
N-No way.
ま　まさか
Naomi?!
ナオミ
Where are you?
どこだ
Where did you go, Naomi?!
どこに行ったの　ナオミ
Are we being attacked?!
敵の攻撃？
Impossible.
莫迦な　何の気配もなかったぞ
I didn't sense anything off.
Naomi!
ナオミ
Be careful, Tanizaki-san!
谷崎さん　危険です
Where are you, Elise-chan?
どこだ　エリスちゃん
Well, I'm in trouble now.
困ったねぇ
Give Naomi back!
ナオミを返せ
Found you!
見つけた
Wait!
待てー
Let's play.
遊びましょ
Welcome, everyone, to Anne's Chamber.
皆さん　ようこそ　アンの部屋へ
Oh, this is embarrassing.
あら　嫌だわ
So many people are looking right at me.
こんな沢山の方達に見詰められて
I'm not very good at talking to strangers.
あたし　初対面の方とお話しするの苦手なの
But that won't do.
でも駄目ね　ちゃんと説明しなくちゃ　皆さんお困りだわ
I have to give a proper explanation,
or everyone will be so lost.
After all, you were brought
to this strange place out of the blue.
だって　こんな見知らぬ場所に突然連れて来られたんですもの
If I were you,
my heart would be pounding—
あたしだったら心臓が飛び跳ねてしまうことでしょ
ナオミはどこだ
Where's Naomi?
Oh, I'm sorry.
あらごめんなさい
I should explain that first.
その説明が最初よね
Your agents are over there.
探偵社の皆さんはあちらよ
Kenji-kun!
賢治君　ナオミ
Naomi!
Damn it!
くそ　ナオミ
Naomi!
鍵なしでは開かないわ
It won't open without the key.
That one opens, though.
開くのはあっち
They're all frozen.
静止してる
Has time come to a stop?
時間が止まってる
My name is Lucy.
あたしの名前はルーシー
This is a dimension
I created with my ability.
ここはあたしの異能力で創った空間なの
But don't worry,
でも安心なさって　いつでもその白いドアから出られるわ
you can leave whenever you want,
through that white door.
That is, if you don't want
your colleagues back.
お仲間を取り返したくなければですけど
What do you want?
どうする心算だ
That's easy.
簡単よ
I just want you to play
with Anne in this chamber.
この部屋のアンと遊んでいただきたいの
Come, Anne.
いらっしゃい　アン
Guild
Apprentice
Lucy M
Ability:
Anne of
Abyssal
Red
Anne loves to play.
アンは遊ぶのが大好きなの
She's a bit needy, but she's quite cute.
少し甘えん坊だけど　可愛いのよ
ただしドアから出たら　部屋の中のことは全部忘れちゃうわよ
But if you leave through that door,
you'll forget everything
that happened in this room.
Do you get it, now?
よろしくて
Oh, my.
あらあら
Only three of you are left?
残ったのは三人だけ？
It's not safe here.
ここは危険です　逃げたほうがいい
You should run.
I'm looking for a girl.
女の子を探してるんだ
She's lovely, just like an angel.
天使のように可愛い子なのだよ
Have you see her?
どこかで見なかったかな
No, I'm sorry to say.
いえ　残念ながら
I see.
そうかい
Her name is Elise-chan.
エリスちゃんと云う名でね
Anyways, ever since we've been separated,
とにかく　この子と逸れて　私はもう気が気でなくって
I've been beside myself.
She may be behind that door.
あの扉の向こうにいるかもしれない
If that's the case,
もしそうなら　今逃げたら一生後悔する
I'll regret running away
for the rest of my life.
So I'll stay, too.
だから　私も残るよ
Okay.
わかりました
The rules are simple.
ルールは簡単よ
Play tag with my lovely Anne.
可愛いアンと追いかけっこをして　タッチされたら皆さんの負け
If she tags you, you lose.
If you can open the door using that key
before she catches you, you win.
捕まる前に　その鍵でドアを開ければ　皆さんの勝ちよ
人質をお返しするわ
I'll return the hostages.
Well?
それで　参加されるのは誰
Who's in?
二人同時でもいいのか
Can two play at once?
Of course.
勿論よくってよ
The more the merrier.
お遊戯はみんなのほうが楽しいもの
We can win if we use Tanizaki-san's
Light Snow ability to project illusions.
谷崎さんの空間に虚像を映し出す「細雪」があれば勝てる
Are you ready?
準備はよろしくて？
Yeah.
ああ
Ready,
レディー…
Go!
ゴー！
She's fast!
速い
Caught
一人目
the first one!
捕・ま・え・た
Tanizaki-san!
谷崎さん
We've made yet another friend.
またお友達が増えちゃったわ
What a great day, Anne.
嬉しいわね　アン
What? What's that?
なーに　まだ欲しいの？
You want more?
Well, then.
それじゃあ…
Wow, amazing!
すごいすごーい
I want to see more.
もっと見たいわ
What a strong, useful ability.
なんて力強くて便利な異能力なんでしょう
I'm sure you were sought after
from the moment you were born.
さぞ幼少からちやほやされたに違いないわ
I heard you're an orphan.
あなた　元孤児なんですってね
I grew up in an orphanage, too.
あたしも孤児院育ちなの
It was a very cold place.
とても寒い処よ
After using ice-cold
rags to clean all day,
氷のような冷たい水で一日雑巾がけをした後は
my fingers would ache constantly.
何日も指の痛みが取れなかったわ
Given my ability,
それにあたしの異能はこんなだから　みんなに鬼魅悪がられちゃって
everyone thought I was a freak.
あなたが捕われた時　探偵社は必死で探したそうね
I heard the Agency was desperate
to find you when you were taken.
How wonderful.
素敵だわ　きっとあなたがいい異能を持っているからなのね
It must be because you have a great ability.
I...
僕は…
The Guild took me in because they
saw potential in my ability, too.
あたしも異能を買われてギルドに拾われたの
But there is no room for error in The Guild.
けどギルドは失敗を許さないわ
If I fail in this mission,
今回の作戦をしくじったら　汚れた紙ナプキンのように捨てられる
I will be tossed aside
like a used napkin.
Then I'll be all alone again.
そしたらまた独りよ
Hey,
ねえ
why does it have to be you?
何故あなたなの
Why can't it be me?
何故私ではないの
It's so unfair.
不公平よ
あなたもあたしの気持ちを思い知るべきだわ
You should know how I feel, too!
You should stay in this room forever!
この部屋の中で　永遠にね
The only way out is to put
the key in that door.
あのドアに鍵を挿すしか勝つ方法はない
Okay!
よし　勝った
I win!
Watch out, boy!
少年　危ない
What?
Be careful, this key is important.
あらあら　大事の鍵なのに
I thought I'd win if I opened
the door with the key!
鍵でドアを開けたら勝ちじゃないのか
That's right. If you could open it.
そう　開けられればね
I have no idea how to use
a key like this, myself.
こんな鍵をどう使うのか　あたしも見当がつかないけど
So there was never a way
to win in the first place.
最初から勝つ方法なんてなかったんだ
The real game starts now.
お遊戯はこれからが本番よ
Looks like you're a natural at tag,
あなたは鬼遊の天才みたいだけど
この状態で何分心が持つかしら
but I wonder how long
you can last like this.
There's no way to fight back.
打つ手がない　いつかは捕まる
I'll eventually be caught.
I can't possibly hope win now.
ここから逆転なんて　僕には無理だ
I have no choice but to hope that
Dazai-san and the others will come!
もう太宰さん達を頼るしかない
You're going to run away,
leaving your friends behind?
お友達を捨てて逃げる気？
Even if he were in this situation,
この状況でも太宰さんならきっと何かを思いつく
Dazai-san would think of something!
But I can't!
でも僕には無理だ
No, boy.
駄目だよ　少年
Your enemy lies that way.
敵はあっちだ
I wouldn't advise running away
in this particular case.
この場合での逃亡はお勧めしない
Er, that is,
いやその…　高が街医者の言葉を信じてもらえるならばだが
if you'd trust the words of your
local neighborhood physician.
If you were to believe her words,
彼女の言葉を信じるなら　そのドアから逃げれば君は記憶を失う
you'll forget everything once
you leave through that door.
You won't remember
the enemy's plan,
敵の手管も捕らえられた仲間の危機も忘れ
nor your colleagues in danger.
And the enemy will continue
to press her attack.
敵は進撃を続ける
I'll teach you something useful.
よいことを教えよ
In game theory,
戦戯理論では　危害を加えてきた敵には
the optimal strategy is to launch
徹底反撃を行うのが理論最適解とされている
a total counteroffensive on an
enemy who has attacked you.
Crush the enemy.
徹底的に叩くのだ
But how?
でも方法が
An arrogant enemy who feels invincible
絶対に敗けぬと高を括る敵ほど容易い相手はいないよ
is the most vulnerable opponent of all.
And did I hear right, that
the ones beyond that door
そもそも　あの扉の奥にいる彼らは
君が囚われた時
are the very ones who desperately
tried to save you when you were taken?
必死に助けたという話ではなかったのかね
That's right.
そうだ　みんなは僕を助けてくれた
They all saved me.
Are you done with your chit-chat?
お話は終わり？
Have you regained your motivation?
やる気は戻ったのかしら
It's my turn, then.
なら今回は僕の番だ
That's right.
そう
That is your optimal solution.
それが君の最適解だ
It wouldn't be fun any other way.
そうでなくちゃ面白くないわ
But...
でも…
It's already over.
もう終わりよ
Another one!
もう一体
Of course! There are two of you.
そちらは二人なんだから当然でしょ
Shit!
しまった
All right, that's that.
はい　おしまーい
So, what will you do, mister?
それで　おじさまはどうなさるの
Thanks to you,
おじさまの言葉のおかげで　虎の彼に逃げられずに済んだわ
the tiger didn't get away.
So I could let you go as a
sign of my appreciation.
だから　感謝の印に見逃してあげてもいいわよ
Or maybe I want to see your expression
when Anne catches you.
それとも　おじさまがアンに捕まった時の顔を見てみようかしら
Do you want to try me?
試してみるかね
What? What's going on?
なに　何なのこれ
My legs are trembling
so much, I can't move.
脚が震えて動けない
Is this pure malice?
これは…殺気？
But why can't Anne move, either?
でも　アンまで動けないなんて
It won't work.
無理だな
You've already lost.
何故なら君は既に敗けている
Look at the door.
ドアを見るといい
What?!
なに
But I know I shut the door.
ドアは確かに閉まった筈なのに
Why?
どうして
You've made one mistake.
君の見落は一つ
This fight was two against
one from the very start!
この戦いは最初から二対一だ
The moment the door opened,
ドアが開いた瞬間に　谷崎さんの「細雪」で扉の映像を偽装した
Tanizaki-san used his Light Snow
ability to create a false door.
Impossible.
そんな…
And you were able to resist the force
そのうえ　部屋へと吸い込む力に腕力だけで抵抗するなんて
sucking you into the room with
your arms and legs alone?
You misunderstand me.
君は思い違いをしている
I am not strong, and I'm not popular.
僕は強くも人気者でもない
Rather, I've led a cursed life.
むしろ生きることはずっと呪いだった
That's why I understand your jealousy
and hatred of others all too well.
だから他人を妬み怨む君の気持ちはよくわかる
I really don't  want you
to fail this mission!
本当は君にこの作戦を失敗してほしくない
Or lose the place where
you feel you can belong!
居場所を失ってほしくない
But because I'm weak and inexperienced,
でも　僕は弱くて未熟だから他に方法が思いつかない
I can't think of any other way!
What?
This is...
これは…
I tied a ribbon to you.
飾帯を君に結んでおいた
Release your ability and let everyone go!
異能力を解除してみんなを解放しろ
Or I'll drag you into the room.
でないと君を奥の部屋に引きずり込む
Without a key, the door won't open.
鍵がなければ扉は開かない
That means if you're imprisoned inside,
なら君が幽閉されれば　扉を開けられる者は誰もいなくなる
no one can ever open that door.
If that happens, you won't
be able to return to reality
そうなってから能力を解除しても　君は元の世界に戻れない
even if you release your ability.
Am I wrong?
違うか
That's...
それは…
Our abilities aren't convenient tools
made to control other people.
異能力は便利な支配道具じゃない　それは僕がよくわかってる
I know that better than most.
Do you want to be trapped in the dimension
of your own making until you die—
自分で創った空間に死ぬまで
No, even after you die?
いや　死んだ後も囚われ続けたいか
I—I can't afford to fail!
あ…あたしは失敗するわけには
I'm going to let go.
今から手を離す
You only have that split second
before the door closes to decide.
決断の時間は扉が閉まる一瞬しかないよ
No, wait!
駄目　待て
Um, hey...
あの…君
If I...
もし僕に何かできることが…
If I can do anything for you...
Um!
あの
Oh, Elise-chan!
エリスちゃん
Are you okay?!
もう大丈夫だったかい
Where have you been?!
どこに行っていたのだい　心配したのだよ
I was so worried!
You just up and vanished.
突然いなくなるから
I thought Rintarou would worry
if I suddenly disappeared.
急に消えたら　リンタロウが心配するかなーと思って
I wanted to make Rintarou cry.
リンタロウを泣かせたくなった
That's so mean, Elise-chan!
非道いよ　エリスちゃん
でも可愛いから許す
But I forgive you, because you're so cute!
Kyouka-chan?
鏡花ちゃん
You came to get me?
迎えに来てくれたの
I was worried.
心配した
Thank you.
ありがとう
We'll be taking our leave now.
それでは　私達は失礼するよ
Thank you for your advice earlier.
先程助言　有り難う御座いました
So, you're a doctor?
そういえば　お医者さんなのですか
Ex-doctor.
元医者だよ
Right now, I'm just a middle-aged man
今は小さな寄合の仕切屋中年さ
keeping a small group of people in line.
Boy,
少年
a logical, optimal solution exists
in any wartime situation,
どんな困難な戦局でも　必ず理論的な最適解はある
no matter how difficult the challenge.
You must not forget that,
especially in times of confusion
混乱して自棄になりそうな時ほど　それを忘れてはいけないよ
when you might feel
inclined to recklessness.
Okay.
はい
Goodbye, then.
ではでは
There is a way, even in difficult times.
困難な時でも道はある…か
What's wrong, Kyouka-chan?
鏡花ちゃん　どうしたの
Kyouka-chan?
鏡花ちゃん？
Kyouka-chan!
I had a good time.
楽しい一時だった
I wanted to return to my younger days
私も童心に返って　異能力で敵をばっさばさとやっつけたくなったよ
and use my ability to mow down
my enemies left and right.
You're too old for that!
中年には無理
That's so mean.
非道い
I may not look like much, but...
私はこれでも
So this is a Guild assassin?
これがギルドの刺客かね
Yes, sir.
はい
The Agency and The Guild...
探偵社にギルド
It seems we are in a challenging
wartime situation ourselves.
我々もまた困難な戦局というわけだ
We need an optimal solution.
Port
Mafia
Leader
Mori
Ougai
最適解が必要だね
The Agency and The Guild...
探偵社もギルドも
Ability:
Vita
Sexualis
Those who oppose us will be crushed,
敵対者は徹底的に潰して　殺す
and annihilated.
To Be Continued
boku ga boku de irareru
I was searching for the reason
僕が僕でいられる　理由を探していた
riyuu o sagashiteita
why I'm able to stay as I am.
anata no mune no naka de
If there's a version of me
あなたの胸の中で　生きている僕がいるのならば
ikiteiru boku ga iru no naraba
that exists in your heart,
kurayami mo nagai sakamichi mo
Then even if darkness looms on this rocky road,
暗闇も長い坂道も　越えて行けるような僕になれるはず
koeteikeru you na boku ni nareru hazu
I'll be able to find the way to the new me.
sorezore ni ima o aruiteru bokura ga waraeru you ni
So that we can keep smiling in our own moments,
それぞれに今を歩いてる僕らが笑えるように
ikiteiru imi o tashikameainagara susumeru you ni
So that we can explore the meaning of life together,
生きている意味を確かめ合いながら進めるように
namae o yobu yo anata no namae o
I'll call out a name, your name.
名前を呼ぶよ　あなたの名前を
anata ga anata de ireru you ni
So that you can stay how you are.
あなたがあなたでいれるように
kanashimi ni kurete anata no namida ga koboreru toki
Whenever you're overcome by grief, and tears flow,
悲しみに暮れてあなたの涙がこぼれる時
samishisa ni afureta kokoro ga shibondeku toki
Whenever your heart floods with loneliness and you waste away,
寂しさに溢れて心がしぼんでく時
namae o yobu yo anata no namae o
I'll call out a name, your name.
名前を呼ぶよ　あなたの名前を
僕の名前を呼んでくれたみたいに
boku no namae o yondekureta mitai ni
Just as you once called out mine.